Edwin Edgar Voigt Papers
Edwin Edgar Voigt Papers
1932-1963
Voigt, Edwin Edgar, 1892-
7.0 linear ft.
Papers of the American Methodist clergyman and educator. Correspondence, general files, material related to the Council of Bishops, and manuscript sermons (1932-1963).
148720
Biographical History
Edwin Edgar Voigt (1892-1977) was an American Methodist clergyman and educator. He received a BS (1917) and MA (1922) from Northwestern University; a BD (1921) and DD (1942) from Garrett Bible Institute in Evanston, Illinois; and a PhD from Yale University in 1924. After teaching at both Northwestern University and the Garrett Bible Institute, Voigt served as an associate pastor at the First Methodist Church of Evanston, Illinois from 1932 to 1936. From 1936 to 1942, he was pastor of the First Methodist Church and director of the Wesley Foundation in Iowa City. He became president of Simpson College in 1942. In 1952 he resigned from Simpson and was elected a bishop of the Methodist Church, serving in the Dakota Area district 1952-1960 and the Illinois Area 1960-1964. From 1964 to 1968 he was president of McKendree College in Lebanon Illinois. He was also the author of several books including Biblical Hebrew for Beginners and Methodist Worship in the Church Universal.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Edwin Edgar Voigt Papers are arranged in ten categories.
Correspondence-agencies and boards contains items from the various administrative boards and committees Voigt served on, including the Wesley Foundation.
Correspondence-general and business contains other correspondence.
Council of Bishops contains correspondence with other Methodist bishops.
Dakotas contains items from Voigt's time as bishop of the Dakota Area.
Elections contains correspondence related to his election as a Methodist bishop.
Illinois contains items from his time as the bishop of the Illinois Area.
McKendree contains items from his time as the president of McKendree College.
Miscellaneous contains academic materials including lectures and items related to Voigt's various articles and books.
Sermons contains the text of sermons Voigt gave as pastor at Evanston and Iowa City and as bishop of the Dakotas and Illinois Areas.
Simpson College contains items related to his time spent as President of Simpson College.
Arrangement of the Collection
Subjects in each category are arranged alphabetically. Sermons are arranged chronologically.
Subject and Genre Headings
Church and clergy; Voigt, Edwin Edgar, 1892-; Clergy -- United States.; Methodist Church -- Clergy.; Methodists -- United States.; Sermons, American.; Correspondence.; Sermons.; Clergy.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence-agencies and boards
  - Board of Education
    - Division of Higher Education Bulletin (Box 1)
    - Division of Local Church (Box 1)
    - Editorial Division (Box 1)
    - John 0. Gross ministerial training (Box 1)
    - Myron Wicks (Box 1)
    - Theological education (Box 1)
    - Wesley Foundation, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Board of Evangelism (Box 1)
  - Board of Missions
    - Ashton Almond, Tres. (Box 1)
    - Department of Town and County (Box 1)
    - Director Department of Local Church (Box 1)
    - Division of National Missions (Box 1)
    - Division of World Missions (Box 1)
    - Missionary personnel (Box 1)
    - Women's Division of Christian Service (Box 1)
  - Board of Pensions (Box 1)
  - Christian Vocations Committee (Box 1)
  - Christian Vocations, Interboard Committee
    - Regional meetings (Box 1)
  - Council on World Service and Finance (Box 1)
  - Interboard Committee on Christian Vocations (Box 1)
  - Study Commission on Theological Education (Box 1)
  - University Senate (Box 1)
  - Vocations (Box 1)
- Correspondence-general and business
  - Anderson, Arlow (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Hurst (Box 1)
  - Approved evangelists (Box 1)
  - B-miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Baker, Dr. Eric (Box 1)
  - Baker University (Box 1)
  - Barnett, Albert (Box 1)
  - Bosley, Harold A. (Box 1)
  - Bucke, Emory Stevens (Box 1)
  - Bullis, Harry A. (Box 1)
  - C-miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Centenary program (Box 1)
  - Chambers, Arthur A. (Box 1)
  - Church architecture (Box 1)
  - Church, Marguerite Stitt, congresswoman (Box 1)
  - Church Music Workshop, 1961 (Box 1)
  - Church Union Committee (Box 1)
  - D-miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Denman, Harry (Box 1)
  - Dickhaut, John W. (Box 1)
  - Dyk, Leroy (Box 1)
  - E-miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Eastern Asia Trip (Box 1)
  - F-miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Foreign correspondence (Box 1)
  - G-miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Garrett Bible Institute (Box 1)
  - General Conference, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Georgia Pastors' School (Box 1)
  - Goff, Charles Ray (Box 1)
  - H-miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Holter Inauguration (Box 1)
  - Hyde, Melvin W. (Box 1)
  - Hymn Society of America (Box 1)
  - I-miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Iliff School of Theology, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - India
    - Central Conference, 1961 (Box 1)
    - India Church Union (Box 1)
    - Correspondence (Box 1)
    - Itinerary, 1960-1961 (Box 2)
    - Reports (Box 2)
  - Irwin, John C. (Box 2)
  - J-miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - James, James (Box 2)
  - K-miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Kansas (Box 2)
  - Kendall College (Box 2)
  - Kennedy, John F. (Box 2)
  - Kirkpatrick, Dow Koontz (Box 2)
  - Kresge Foundation (Box 2)
  - L-miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Law, William G. (Box 2)
  - Lee, Mrs. Y.O. (Box 2)
  - Lindstrom, David E. (Box 2)
  - Louisiana Pastors' School (Box 2)
  - Lovelace, Austin C. (Box 2)
  - M-miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Malaya (Box 2)
  - Martin, Stanley H. (Box 2)
  - Mather, James Rev. (Box 2)
  - Methodist Story, The (Box 2)
  - Minnesota Pastors' School (Box 2)
  - Monohan, Sherman (Box 2)
  - Moore, Arthur Jr. (Box 2)
  - Morris, Sam (Box 2)
  - Mundt, Karl E. (Box 2)
  - N-miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - National education (Box 2)
  - North Central Jurisdiction
    - Committee on Ministerial Recruitment, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Jurisdictional Conference, 1964 (Box 2)
    - Regional Workshop, Jacksonville (Box 2)
  - 0-miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Ohio Wesleyan, Pres. Lockmiller (Box 2)
  - Older Youth Report (Box 2)
  - P-miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Pennington, Chester A. (Box 2)
  - Perkins, E. Benson (Box 2)
  - Quillian, Joseph (Box 2)
  - R-miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Rice, Allen B. (Box 2)
  - Rodman, Earl A. (Box 2)
  - Rural Short Course, 1963 (Box 2)
  - S-miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Rapid City, South Dakota (Box 2)
  - Sahai, Rev. George S. (Box 2)
  - Sargent, Fred W. (Box 2)
  - Seamands, David (Box 2)
  - Shipman, Raymond M. (Box 2)
  - Smith, Rockwell C. (Box 2)
  - Strohl, C. Orville (Box 2)
  - T-miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Teacher Training Certificates (Box 2)
  - Thornburg, Amos A. (Box 2)
  - Tillman, Mrs. J. Fount (Box 2)
  - Trott, Norman L. (Box 2)
  - U-miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Usman, K. M. Rev., India (Box 2)
  - V-miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Virginia Pastors' School (Box 2)
  - W-miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Who's Who in America (Box 2)
  - Wiebe, Howard F. (Box 2)
  - World Council of Churches (Box 2)
  - World Methodist Council (Box 2)
  - Worship and Hymnal (Box 2)
  - XYZ-Miscellaneous
- Council of Bishops
  - Council of Bishops (Box 2)
  - New bishops (Box 2)
  - Ralph T. Alton (Box 2)
  - Hobart B. Amstutz (Box 2)
  - Armstrong, James (Box 2)
  - Theodore Arvidson (Box 2)
  - James Chamberlain Baker (Box 2)
  - Hiram Bouz (Box 2)
  - J.W.E. Bowen (Box 2)
  - Charles W. Brashares (Box 2)
  - William R. Cannon (Box 2)
  - Clair, M.W. Jr. (Box 2)
  - D. Stanley Coors (Box 2)
  - Kenneth Copeland (Box 2)
  - Fred T. Corson (Box 2)
  - Ralph Cushman (Box 2)
  - Cana Dawson (Box 2)
  - Roberto Elphick (Box 2)
  - F. Ensley (Box 2)
  - Charles W. Flint (Box 2)
  - Eugene, M. Frank (Box 2)
  - Paul N. Garber (Box 2)
  - Edwin R. Garrison (Box 2)
  - C. F. Golden (Box 2)
  - A. Raymond Grant (Box 3)
  - Odd Hagen (Box 3)
  - Paul Hardin, Jr. (Box 3)
  - N. B. Harmon (Box 3)
  - Bishop Harman (Box 3)
  - Costeu J. Harrell (Box 3)
  - Bachman G. Hodge (Box 3)
  - Ivan Lee Holt (Box 3)
  - F.E. Kearns (Box 3)
  - Gerald H. Kennedy (Box 3)
  - Willis J. King (Box 3)
  - W. Earl Ledden (Box 3)
  - Hyungki J. Lew (Box 3)
  - Lodger, D.E. (Box 3)
  - Lord, J.W. (Box 3)
  - Edgar A. Love (Box 3)
  - J. Ralph MaGee (Box 3)
  - Paul E. Martin (Box 3)
  - W.C. Martin (Box 3)
  - James K. Matthews (Box 3)
  - W. Vernon Middleton (Box 3)
  - George A. Miller (Box 3)
  - Shot K. Mondol (Box 3)
  - Arthur J. Moore (Box 3)
  - Noah W. Moore, Jr. (Box 3)
  - T. Otto Nall (Box 3)
  - Fredrick Buckley Newell (Box 3)
  - H. Clifford Northcott (Box 3)
  - G. Brumley Oxnam (Box 3)
  - Aud Oxnam (Box 3)
  - Everett W. Palmer (Box 3)
  - Glenn R. Phillips (Box 3)
  - J. Waskom Pickett (Box 3)
  - W.K. Pope (Box 3)
  - T.M. Pryor (Box 3)
  - Clare Purcell (Box 3)
  - Richard C. Raines (Box 3)
  - Marshall Reed (Box 3)
  - Clement Rocky (Box 3)
  - Roy Ho Short (Box 3)
  - Ferdinand Sigg (Box 3)
  - Mangel Singh (Box 3)
  - Eugene Slater (Box 3)
  - A. Frank Smith (Box 3)
  - W. Angie Smith (Box 3)
  - J.D. Smith (Box 3)
  - J. McKendre Springer (Box 3)
  - James H. Straughn (Box 3)
  - B. Foster Stockwell (Box 3)
  - John A. Subhan (Box 3)
  - G. Sundaram (Box 3)
  - L.S. Thomas (Box 3)
  - Donald H. Tippett (Box 3)
  - Wade, Raymond J. (Box 3)
  - Ward, Ralph (Box 3)
  - William T. Watkins (Box 3)
  - H. Bascom Watts (Box 3)
  - Webb, Lance (Box 3)
  - Welch, Herbert (Box 3)
  - Hazen G. Werner (Box 3)
  - Lloyd Wicke (Box 3)
  - Fredrich Wunderlich (Box 3)
  - Bishops
    - Deceased (Box 3)
    - Bishop's Mission
      - Louisiana Conference (Box 3)
      - Nov. 18-20, 2 folders (Box 3)
      - N.Y. Oct. 9-11 (Box 3)
    - Retired (Box 3)
  - Committee on Ordination Ritual (Box 3)
  - Judicial Council (Box 3)
  - Mission on the Ministry (Box 3)
  - Ordination procedures (Box 3)
  - Ordinations (Box 3)
- Dakotas
  - Articles, 1952-1960 (Box 3)
  - Beeman, Paul J. (Box 3)
  - Case, Francis H. (Box 3)
  - Conference, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Customs, 1958-1959 (Box 3)
  - Dakotas Area correspondence, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Early, Dr. Jack J. (Box 3)
  - Flint, Robert (Box 3)
  - Foss, Joe (Box 3)
  - Garrett Centennial Committee (Box 3)
  - Garrison (Box 3)
  - General correspondence (Box 3)
  - General letter (Box 3)
  - India Trip, See also Correspondence-general and business: India (Box 3)
  - Kildal, W. Morris (Box 3)
  - Lease (Box 3)
  - Liang, Mrs. Monte (Box 3)
  - Lockridge, F.E. (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Person to Person Article (Box 3)
  - Southeast Asia Expense Account (Box 3)
  - Smith, Matthew (Box 4)
  - Travel-Switzerland (Box 4)
  - Trost, Harold G. (Box 4)
  - Voigt
    - Correspondence A-M (Box 4)
    - Correspondence N-Z (Box 4)
  - Weeks, President I.D. (Box 4)
- Elections
  - Academic friends (Box 4)
  - Bishops (Box 4)
  - Board secretaries (Box 4)
  - Business friends (Box 4)
  - Consecration services (Box 4)
  - Faculty (Box 4)
  - Family (Box 4)
  - Friends, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Ministers (Box 4)
  - Simpson students (Box 4)
  - Trustees (Box 4)
- Illinois
  - Abingdon press action (Box 4)
  - Advent supplement (Box 4)
  - Answered correspondence (Box 4)
  - Anti-communism (Box 4)
  - Area historical data (Box 4)
  - B-miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - Baldwin Boys School (Box 4)
  - Baptisms (Box 4)
  - Bertholf, Lloyd C. (Box 4)
  - Bishops, Retired (Box 4)
  - Brown, Clifford C. (Box 4)
  - C-miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - Central Illinois (Box 4)
  - Christian Advocate (Box 4)
  - Church and State Conference, 1961 (Box 4)
  - Civil defense (Box 4)
  - Civil rights (Box 4)
  - Conference-orders of worship (Box 4)
  - Confirmation classes, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Harvey Dibrell (Box 4)
  - District meetings (Box 4)
  - District superintendent's letter (Box 4)
  - E-miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - E.W.B (Box 4)
  - Gantz (Box 4)
  - R. Benjamin Garrison (Box 4)
  - General, 3 folders (Box 4)
  - H-miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - Conrad P. Heins (Box 4)
  - Chester Herr (Box 4)
  - Illinois Area (Box 4)
  - Illinois Area story (Box 4)
  - Illyes (Box 4)
  - L-miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - Letters, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Lodger, Dwight E. (Box 4)
  - MacMurray (Box 4)
  - Michaelson (Box 4)
  - Ministers-deceased (Box 4)
  - M-N (Box 4)
  - Missionary dinners (Box 4)
  - Najim (Box 4)
  - Ordination programs (Box 4)
  - Pere Marquette (Box 4)
  - Public relations (Box 4)
  - Race relations (Box 4)
  - Ragan, Raye L. (Box 4)
  - Randle (Box 4)
  - Reception (Box 5)
  - S-miscellaneous (Box 5)
  - Saint Paul's Cathedral (Box 5)
  - Simpson, D.L. (Box 5)
  - Southern Illinois, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Southern Illinois Conference, 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Springfield installations (Box 5)
  - Squire (Box 5)
  - Stoody West (Box 5)
  - Supreme Court (Box 5)
  - Thomas Alton Hospital (Box 5)
  - Together-advocate (Box 5)
  - Unclassified (Box 5)
  - United Church Women (Box 5)
  - United Institutions (Box 5)
  - Voigt (Box 5)
  - Wesley Foundation (Box 5)
  - Wilson, Bayne (Box 5)
- McKendree
  - Akers, Milburn P. (Box 5)
  - Allen, Dr. Max (Box 5)
  - Board meetings (Box 5)
  - Committee on Academic Affairs (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Director of Development (Box 5)
  - Faculty Personnel Committee (Box 5)
  - Financial affairs (Box 5)
  - Fund drive (Box 5)
  - Graduate School of Religion (Box 5)
  - Letters, 3 folders (Box 5)
  - McKendree campaign (Box 5)
  - McKendree miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Notes (Box 5)
  - Programs (Box 5)
  - Retirement (Box 5)
  - Trustees, Board of (Box 5)
- Miscellaneous
  - Archeology, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Articles, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Bible (Box 6)
  - Elementary Magazine (Box 6)
  - Hebrew primer (Box 6)
  - Lectures (Box 6)
  - Magazines (16 issues) (Box 6)
  - Publication (Box 6)
  - R.T.N.J. (Box 6)
  - Teaching outlines (Box 6)
  - Together supplement (Box 6)
- Sermons
  - 1932-1936, Evanston (Box 6)
  - 1936
    - Iowa City, Sept.-Dec. (Box 6)
    - Evanston-occasional sermons and addresses (Box 6)
  - 1937
    - Jan.-July (Box 6)
    - Sept.-Dec. (Box 6)
  - 1938
    - Jan.-July (Box 6)
    - Sept.-Dec. (Box 6)
  - 1939
    - Jan.-July (Box 6)
    - Sept.-Dec. (Box 7)
  - 1940
    - Jan.-July (Box 7)
    - Sept.-Dec. (Box 7)
  - 1941, Jan.-July (Box 7)
  - 1942, Sept.-Jan. (Box 7)
  - 1942-1943 (Box 7)
  - 1944-1948 (Box 7)
  - 1949-1950 (Box 7)
  - 1951-1952 (Box 7)
  - 1952-1954, Dakotas (Box 7)
  - 1956 (Box 7)
  - 1957, Dakotas (Box 7)
  - 1957-1958, Radio Talks (Box 7)
  - 1958 (Box 7)
  - 1959, Dakotas (Box 7)
  - 1960-1961 (Box 7)
  - 1962 (Box 7)
  - 1963 (Box 7)
- Simpson College
  - Addresses and articles (Box 7)
  - Berry, Don (Box 7)
  - Bimson, Dean (Box 7)
  - Bishop Oxnam Magee (Box 7)
  - Chapel (Box 7)
  - Hansher, Virgil M. (Box 7)
  - Inauguration (Box 7)
  - Iowa City, 1936-1942 (Box 7)
  - John, Ralph C. (Box 7)
  - Kersetter, William F. (Box 7)
  - Kindred, Arthur J. (Box 8)
  - First letters-Simpson (Box 8)
  - Martin (Box 8)
  - Personal correspondence of inauguration program (Box 8)
  - Saint Boniface (Box 8)
  - Simpson College (Box 8)
  - W.S.U.I. Radio (Box 8)